[
    {
        "questionNo": "Q1.",
        "question": "Assertive sentences are the same as Affirmative",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q2.",
        "question": "Interrogative sentences:",
        "options": [
            "Express queries",
            "Clarify doubts",
            "Enquire about facts",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q3.",
        "question": "You couldn’t play soccer, and Sophia couldn’t do gymnastics. The above sentence is:",
        "options": [
            "Declarative affirmative",
            "Assertive Negative",
            "Optative",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q4.",
        "question": "A sentence may consist of one or more words.",
        "options": [
            "Correct",
            "Incorrect"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q5.",
        "question": "Choose the correct option. Exclamatory sentences might or might not include an exclamatory sign. Exclamatory sentences might or might not include an interjection.",
        "options": [
            "I is correct, II is wrong",
            "I is incorrect, II is right",
            "Both A and B are not valid",
            "Both A and B are correct"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q6.",
        "question": "Do not go outside Shirley. The above sentence is:",
        "options": [
            "A negative sentence",
            "An affirmative sentence",
            "An Imperative sentence.",
            "Both A and C"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q7.",
        "question": "‘Certainly’,  ‘Sorry’, ‘Pardon’ can be used as word-sentences.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q8.",
        "question": "A promise is:",
        "options": [
            "A declarative sentence",
            "An optative sentence",
            "Both A and B",
            "An imperative sentence"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q9.",
        "question": "Imperative sentences include:",
        "options": [
            "Doubts",
            "Suggestions",
            "Commands",
            "Both B and C"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q10.",
        "question": "“Good, we’re going to eat good food every night!” is:",
        "options": [
            "A wish",
            "A positive statement",
            "An exclamatory sentence",
            "Both B and C"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q11.",
        "question": "I slept. The above sentence is a declarative sentence.",
        "options": [
            "Correct",
            "Incorrect"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q12.",
        "question": "Which of these sentences are in the imperative form?",
        "options": [
            "Have fun, won’t you?",
            "Did you have fun?",
            "It will definitely be fun!",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q13.",
        "question": "The regular form of a declarative sentence is:",
        "options": [
            "To assert an opinion",
            "Subject-verb",
            "A full-stop or period",
            "Subject-verb"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q14.",
        "question": "The use of not in a question frequently implies that an affirmative answer is expected.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct": 0
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q15.",
        "question": "Which one is an optative sentence:",
        "options": [
            "Long live the king!",
            "May god bless you.",
            "Happy Birthday Sara!",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q16.",
        "question": "Read the extract from the story you have just read and answer the following question: “Does that make sense so far?”",
        "options": [
            "Doubt",
            "Query",
            "Rhetorical question",
            "Is a question that is asked to get a confirmation"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q17.",
        "question": "Which sentence type often begins with a subject?",
        "options": [
            "Optative",
            "Imperative",
            "Exclamative",
            "Declarative"
        ],
        "correct": 3
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q18.",
        "question": "Which is a declarative sentence?",
        "options": [
            "Ouch!",
            "That hurts!",
            "Stop hurting me!",
            "Both B and C"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q19.",
        "question": "“Stand in a line and remain quiet!” The above sentence is:",
        "options": [
            "Exclamative",
            "Imperative",
            "Optative",
            "Both A and B"
        ],
        "correct": 1
    },
    {
        "questionNo": "Q20.",
        "question": "The role of an assertive sentence is to …………someone about something.",
        "options": [
            "Surprise",
            "Order",
            "Tell",
            "Ask"
        ],
        "correct": 2
    }
]
